# **CHRISTOPHER FERRARO**

Ludlow, MA 01056
 7743923956
 christopher.ferraro34@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative Graphic Designer and aspiring Web Developer with a talent for developing unique custom artwork, innovative approach to ideas and concept development. Offering 7 years of experience overseeing induvidual and large scale projects.

SKILLS	React	HTML / CSS
	JavaScript	Bootstrap/ChakraUI
	Express.js	Mongo DB
	VS Code	GitHub
	HTML/CSS	Adobe Creative Suite

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **LEAD SCREENPRINTER 03/2023 TO CURRENT**

The Print Shop, Wilbraham, MA

- Improved cutomer satisfaction with timely order fulfilment and consistent print quality.
- Consistently met deadlines for high-volume orders through effective time management and workflow coordination among team members.

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER (FREELANCE) 09/2023 to Current**

Parlor Skis, Boston, MA

- Create custom ski graphics for individual customer.
- Implemented feedback and suggestions from clients to improve designs.
- Utilized Adobe Creative Suite to develop creative designs.

### PROJECT MANAGER 06/2022 to 03/2023

Mittera

- Successfully managed multiple projects simultaneously by prioritizing tasks according to to urgency, resources availability, and alignment with organizational goals.
- Planned, designed, and scheduled phases for large projects.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Met project deadlines without sacrificing build quality or workplace saftey}.$
- Achieved project deadlines by coordinating with contractors to manage performance.

#### PRINT PRODUCTION MANAGER 03/2021 to 06/2022

Kastlfel/Denver Print House

- Constructed a production process for rapidly increasing production levels.
- Created and maintained a productin schedule for each department involved in production.
   The production schedule showed all relevant aspects of the job.
- Oversaw 50 employees and kept workflow consistant through a shift.
- Initiated a Performance Incentive Program to increase employee engagement.
- Hired and trained new employees.

#### COLOR SEPARATION SPECALIST 01/2020 to 03/2021

Kastlfel/Denver Print House

- Implimented a naming convention to store and find files. This was company wide implimentation to aid in efficiency and productivity.
- Pioneered new non destructive ways to most effectively prepare art files for production. This
  was accomplished by linking files that were seperated on different programs and utilizing
  tools in the programs that were not previously being used.
- Mastered separation techniques that are used at the highest level of color separation.

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER 05/2019 to 12/2019**

Real Tech Innovations (College Startup Company)

- Created graphics and web icons for client web pages
- Created webpage content and managed company websites through WordPress.
- Wrote blog posts on the importance of cyber security for small businesses.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BFA: 05/2018

University of Massachusetts Dartmouth

### CERTIFICATE: Full Stack Web Development 04/2024

University of Central Florida

# HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Snowboarding
- Hiking
- Surfing
- Drawing
- Woodworking

# CHRISTOPHER FERRARO

• Ludlow, MA 01056 • 7743923956 • christopher.ferraro34@gmail.com